welcome back to another audacity
欢迎回到另一个大胆的地方
tutorial in this video I want to talk
这个视频中的教程我想谈谈
about monitoring your audio and what to
关于监听您的音频以及要做的事情
look for to know if your audio is too
查看以了解您的音频是否太
low or too high or good quality or bad
低或太高或质量好或差
quality so I want if you look up here
所以我想要质量 如果你看这里的话
under R we have a microphone and a
在R下面 我们有一个麦克风和一个
speaker's kind of button it says click
扬声器的按钮 它说点击
to start monitoring if we click up here
如果我们点击这里开始监控
we notice we start seeing some levels so
我们注意到我们开始看到一些级别 所以
I'm talking right now and as I talk
我现在在说话 就在我说话的时候
these levels kind of go up and the
这些水平会上升 然后
microphone I'm using to monitor here is
我用来监听的麦克风是
not the same microphone I'm talking into
不是对着我说话的那个麦克风
for recording this audio the one
录制这段音频的那个人
recording the audio on is this road mic
正在录制音频的是这个道路上的麦克风
and the one that we're seeing right now
而我们现在看到的就是
up here is our is my webcam microphone
上面是我们的是我的网络摄像头麦克风
and I can control the volume of this
我可以控制这个的音量
over here by just clicking and dragging
只需点击并拖动即可
this down so if I bring this down here
如果我把这个拿下来
we see this doesn't go up quite as high
我们看到这个不是很高
when I talk I bring it all the way down
当我说话的时候 我会把它一直带下去
it's pretty low now it's only kind about
现在已经很低了 只是
halfway if I bring it all the way up we
如果我把它带到半路上 我们
see it goes this these bars go higher so
看这个 这些栅栏更高 所以
this is showing a representation of the
这显示的是
audio that we're recording also when I
我们录制的音频也是当我
when it's silent we see the noise floor
当它寂静的时候 我们看到喧闹的地板
so we see how much ambient noise there
所以我们可以看到有多少环境噪音
is happening you see that so it's just
正在发生 你看到了 所以它只是
some noise happening in the air in this
空气中出现了一些噪音
room that the buzzing of the computer or
房间里有电脑的嗡嗡声还是
buzzing of lights that's just the noise
灯光的嗡嗡声 那只是噪音
that it's picking up there's a left and
它正在加速 在那里有一个左转弯
a right channel that's why they're kind
一个正确的频道 这就是为什么他们很友好
of ones ahead of the other sometimes we
有时我们会比别人更早
see left and right and this is too high
左右看 这个太高了
right now so I'm not recording but we
现在 所以我没有录音 但我们
see this is pretty high too the fact
看 这太高了 事实是
that that's going into orange and even
它会变成橙色 甚至
red if I were to clap my hands
如果我拍手 我就会发红
it definitely Peaks out we can record
它肯定会达到顶峰 我们可以录制
and see what that looks like so this is
看看它是什么样子 这是
recording I'm gonna come really close
录制时 我会非常接近
and talk right into this microphone here
对着这个麦克风说话
and we see it's like clipping
我们看到这就像是剪裁
it's just too loud a good level for this
声音太大了 这是一个很好的水平
would be to come down here maybe set it
可能是来这里 也许把它放在
to right here so that it goes into the
就在这里 这样它就会进入
yellow occasionally when things get
当事情变得很糟糕时 偶尔会变黄
really loud it might barely start to
声音很大 可能几乎不会开始
clip a little bit but we want to avoid
剪了一点 但我们想避免
clipping I'm gonna hit stop here on this
剪报我要在这里停下来
recording so clipping is when if we come
录制这样的剪辑是当我们来的时候
over here to when I was really close
在这里 当我真的很接近的时候
when the audio file goes up above this
当音频文件位于此上方时
1.0 point so it starts at 0
1.0分 所以从0开始
and then one is like 100% so if your
然后一个是100% 所以如果你的
audio that you're recording is over 100%
您正在录制的音频超过100%
level then you're going to experience
然后你就会体验到
clipping which the top of this wave
剪裁这一波的顶部
clips a good healthy wave looks like
剪辑好的健康波浪看起来像是
this you can see the very top of it and
你可以看到它的最顶端
you can see what the wave looks like if
你可以看到波浪是什么样子的 如果
we want to zoom in and look at like a
我们想要放大并像一个
good healthy way we can highlight this
我们可以通过良好的健康方式突出这一点
and then go to this click here it says
然后转到这个点击这里 上面写着
fit selection to width and we can just
使所选内容适合宽度 我们可以
see we can see the tops and we can see
看 我们能看到顶部 我们能看到
the whole wave and there's space above
整个海浪和上面的空间
it if ever we come over and we see a
如果有一天我们走过去 看到一个
wave and there's not space above it like
波浪 上面没有空间 就像
this over here you see it's it's clipped
这个在这里 你看 它是被剪断的
out part of the audio click here so we
部分音频点击此处 因此我们
can see that so these parts of the audio
我可以看到 音频的这些部分
are clipped and it sounds pretty bad too
都被剪短了 听起来也很糟糕
when this happens so if we go back to
当这种情况发生时 如果我们回到
the beginning and play this see that
一开始就玩这个看那个
it's like all distorted and look at our
这一切都被扭曲了 看看我们的
levels on our playback when we're
我们的回放水平 当我们
playing we can see basically our speaker
播放时 我们基本上可以看到我们的扬声器
is showing the same thing that our
所展示的与我们的
recording monitor was showing when we
当我们播放录音监视器的时候
recorded so we can we can go in and fix
录音 这样我们就可以进去修理
this after the fact using different
这是事后使用的不同
effects but the best thing to do is just
效果 但最好的做法是
record it right the first time and so
第一次就录好了 所以
for example like if we want to just
例如 如果我们想要
lower the volume watch what'll happen we
把音量调低 看看我们会发生什么
can click here and we can turn down the
可以点击这里 我们可以调低
gain and that'll actually lower it
收益 这实际上会降低它
doesn't change the wave but it's gonna
不会改变波浪 但它会
make it much quieter when we playback so
当我们播放时 让它变得更安静
it's like you can almost hardly hear it
就像你几乎听不到一样
but it's still distorted even though we
但它仍然是扭曲的 即使我们
turned it down that the distortion still
调低音量 表示失真仍然存在
there because we captured it with this
因为我们用这个捕捉到了它
kind of crazy distortion this left and
留下了一种疯狂的扭曲
right I want to show - on the audio
对 我想展示--在音频上
track just lets us control whether we're
赛道只是让我们控制我们是否
using our left or right
使用我们的左侧或右侧
whether that audio is coming out of the
无论音频是从
left or the right ear just download it
左耳或右耳下载即可
so it's not so loud for you so this is
所以这对你来说不是很吵 所以这是
the left side this is the right side if
左侧这是右侧 如果
we hit record again oh wait let's go
我们又创了纪录 哦 等等 我们走吧
back and hit record again a second time
返回并再次刷新记录
Oh am i setting okay so nevermind
哦 我准备好了吗 所以没关系
in the next video we'll look at adding
在下一个视频中 我们将查看如何添加
in a second track I think there's like a
在第二首曲目中 我认为有一首歌
setting up here we go to edit tracks we
在这里设置 我们要编辑我们的曲目
go to add new stereo track and now we
转到添加新的立体声音轨 现在我们
have a new track down here so we can
在这里有一条新的赛道 这样我们就可以
have two tracks at once it used to be by
一次有两首曲目它曾经是由
default that when you hit record it
默认情况下 当您点击录制它时
would start on a second track and we can
将在第二条轨道上开始 我们可以
change that setting but I'm not sure how
更改该设置 但我不确定如何更改
to do it exactly right now but so now we
去做这件事 但现在我们
can say we can record down in this track
我可以说我们可以在这首曲子里录下来
so this is my second track so we can
这是我的第二首曲目 所以我们可以
have two audio playing overtop of audio
在音频之上播放两个音频
and then we can mute just this one or we
然后我们可以只把这一个静音 或者我们
can solo and just play this one and mute
可以独奏 只演奏这首曲子 然后静音
all the other tracks size of that mute
所有其他音轨的大小都是那个哑巴
and solo is and then we can minimize the
而单人是 然后我们可以最小化
track and kind of bring it down smaller
轨道和某种程度上把它拉得更小
if we're working with lots of different
如果我们处理的是许多不同的
audio tracks you can change the size
您可以更改音轨的大小
that you're viewing it too well I hope I
你看得太好了 我希望我
didn't cover too much I hope I didn't
没有报道太多 我希望我没有
get down into crazy with this tutorial
认真学习这篇教程吧！
but that's what I wanted to talk about
但这正是我想要谈的
is just being aware of your levels and
就是意识到你的水平和
recording good audio and just watching
录制好的音频 只需观看
that you're in that green watching that
你穿着绿色的衣服看着那个
you're recording a nice nice level right
你正在记录一个很好的水平对吗
here just in the green area not into the
就在这里的绿色区域 而不是进入
yellow and also not too low here if it's
黄色 也不会太低 如果它是
too low then your audio sounds you know
太低 那么你的音频听起来你知道
obviously too low but lower it's better
显然太低了 但越低越好
than higher too soft
比高太软
we can always amplify and bring out some
我们总是可以放大并带出一些
of that audio too loud you're gonna get
声音太大你会听到
distortion sounding and that's just no
失真的声音 这只是不
good well I appreciate you watching this
很好很感谢你看这个
video I hope that's been informative for
视频 我希望这是信息
you go ahead and like subscribe comment
你继续 喜欢订阅评论
below and I'll catch you on the next one
下一个我会赶上你